tescodvdrental.com 2006-06-16

# Tesco DVD Rentals - the easiest way to rent DVDs

Tesco DVD Rental recognises that your privacy is very important to you and that it is your right to control your personal information. We know that providing personal information is an act of trust and we take that trust seriously. Tesco DVD Rental will _never_ sell, rent or otherwise disclose any of your personal information, including your Email address, to any third party without your consent. Unless you give us specific consent to act otherwise, the following policies will govern how Tesco DVD Rental handles the personal information that you provide to us.

This Privacy Policy sets out: 

  * Collection and use of information
  * Information storage
  * Information sharing and disclosure
  * Security and prevention against loss, misuse or alteration of information
  * Your ability to edit and cancel your account
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * Contact details

### Collection and use of information

Tesco DVD Rental collects personally identifiable information when you subscribe to the Tesco DVD Rental service.

**What we collect**  
---  
  
  * Nickname
  * Full name
  * Email address
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Mobile telephone number (optional)
  * Credit card type
  * Credit card number
  * Credit card expiry date
  * Gender
  * Date of birth

**How we use it**  
  
  * To check that a credit card is valid
  * To pay your account
  * To send you DVDs you would like to rent
  * To recommend other movies you may like to rent
  * To display your favourites list to others
  * To communicate with you on Tesco DVD Rental-related matters
  * To provide you with order and billing history information

We may collect additional information in connection with your participation in any promotions or competitions offered by us and information you provide when giving us feedback or completing profile forms. 

When you visit the site, Tesco DVD Rental collects additional information about you in order to provide the service. 

**What we collect**  
---  
  
  * Movies you have rented
  * Movies you would like to rent
  * Your movie ratings
  * Your movie reviews

**How we use it**  
  
  * To send you DVDs you would like to rent
  * To establish rental trends in order to recommend other movies you may like to rent

## Information storage

All information you provide to us is stored in the UK only on secure servers that are protected in secure facilites including firewall protection.

## Cookies

Tesco DVD Rental uses cookies to help speed up the login process and for security purposes. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your web browser from a web server and stored on your computer.

Tesco DVD Rental may store up to two types of cookie on your computer:

  1. A unique ID is stored in a _permanent_ cookie so that you do not need to retype information every time you visit our site.
  2. Your web browser's session identification is stored in a _temporary_ cookie to help prevent unauthorised use of your account.

More detailed information on cookies may be found in the Help section of your web browser.   

## Information sharing and disclosure

Tesco DVD Rental is committed to protecting your personal information. We will not disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent except where:

  1. Tesco DVD Rental is required by law to disclose information to third parties.
  2. the service is necessary for the performance of our operations ie. mail delivery, hosting services, protecting us from fraud, and payment of your account.
  3. Tesco DVD Rental buys or sells subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions customer information is one of the transferred assets, but would remain subject to the commitments made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy or equivalent.

Companies and individuals registered in the Tesco DVD Rental Affiliate Program receive aggregate information about customers that they direct to Tesco DVD Rental through links on their website. No personally identifiable information is provided to affiliate members ; the information collected from our affiliates is used strictly for the affiliates program and will not be used for general marketing purposes.

Tesco DVD Rental also provides analyses of our customers in the aggregate to prospective partners, advertisers, movie distributors and other third parties. We do this so that we and our business partners can understand you better, and so we can keep bringing you first-rate services. We may also disclose, on an anonymous basis, literal statements made by our customers. At no time, however, will we disclose personal information about specific customers.

Linked websites are not under the control of Tesco DVD Rental and we are not responsible for the conduct of companies linked to our website. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website we advise you to examine their terms and conditions of use. As a subscriber you have certain rights under the Data Protection Act 1998. You have the right to be told what personal information we hold about you on our database. Should you wish to exercise that right, or if you have any questions concerning the Tesco DVD Rental privacy policy please write to us at: Tesco DVD Rental, c/o Video Island Entertainment Ltd, 8 Europa Studios, Victoria Road, London, NW10 6ND

## Security and prevention against loss, misuse or alteration of information

Tesco DVD Rental has implemented technology and security features, as well as strict internal guidelines, to safeguard the privacy of your personal information from unauthorised access or improper use. We will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available.

For transmitting your personal information to us, we use a secure server with a 128-bit SSL certificate which encrypts all of your personal information. This encryption process ensures that the information you give us is protected against unauthorised use.

|     |   
---|---|---  
While we make every effort to ensure that your information is secure on our system, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

Your Tesco DVD Rental account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. You can play an important role in keeping your personal information secure by maintaining the confidentiality of your password used on the Tesco DVD Rental website. We recommend that you change your password from time to time for additional security. Please advise us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

Access authorisation is granted to key Tesco DVD Rental (Video Island Entertainment Ltd.) staff only. Backups are run to prevent loss of information, and our Internet servers are housed in secure facilities.

## Your ability to edit and cancel your account

You can access My Account from every page on the site to update and correct the personal details that we gathered when you subscribed. You must be logged in to access this information. All information is password-protected so no one can access the information but you.

If you decide to cancel your Tesco DVD Rental subscription, your account will be deactivated immediately. However we are required to retain your information for accounting and taxation purposes.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

From time to time, Tesco DVD Rental will review and may edit this policy in accordance with potential changes to our business and as required by law. Tesco DVD Rental reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time. When we do so we will notify you, either by email, a notice on the website or a message on one of the DVD envelopes we ship to you.

## Access rights

You have the right to access the personal data that is held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information Tesco.com holds about you, please write to us at the following address:   
Privacy Officer, Corporate Secretariat, Tesco House, Delamare Road, Cheshunt, Waltham Cross, Hertfordshire EN8 9SL enclosing your postal details and a cheque for £10 payable to 'Tesco.com Ltd. Access right'. 

## Contact details

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact Tesco DVD Rental:

Tesco DVD Rental  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
VIEL, 8 Europa Studios, Victoria Road, London, NW10 6ND, UK  
Email: [privacy@tescodvdrental.com](mailto:privacy@tescodvdrental.com)

This website is operated by Video Island Entertainment Limited ('VIEL') for and on behalf of Tesco DVD Rental. VIEL's details are as follows: registered No: 4749640; Registered Office: Unit 17, Spectrum House, 32-34 Gordon House Road, London NW5 1LP, UK.

This version last updated 13th November 2004.
